[The Heir]
[Episode 11]
Old Madam,
Master Qi of Yihousheng
has come for a visit.
Show him in.
Sift the tea.
["Sift the tea" means "serve tea"
in ancient Huizhou dialect]
Yes.
I'm sure any tea served here
must be excellent, Old Madam.
However, as a rough and coarse man
myself,
I'm unable to discern the charm
within this tea.
No worries.
Even the best tea is meant to be drunk.
Master Qi, where did you come from?
The Chen residence, the Pan residence,
or the Tian residence?
In my opinion,
you have probably
visited all the ink makers
in Huizhou, haven't you?
Old Madam,
I am from out of town.
In order to do business in Huizhou,
I have to visit all the fellow ink makers,
don't I?
On the banquet that day,
I met you for the first time,
yet we didn't get to talk.
It was truly a pity.
So, I came today especially
to pay you a visit, Old Madam.
Old Madam,
I fortunately obtained a painting.
The creator of this work
cannot be identified.
But the content of it
is rather interesting.
Please take a look, Old Madam.
This is...
The pawner of this painting told me
that this scroll shows
how the masters of Li Ink
made ink along the river
after the founder of the South Tang
restored his ancestral surname.
What a spectacle.
Indeed.
Old Madam,
I took the liberty to call on you today
because I think
that Li Ink is the perfect home
for this painting.
How very nice.
Here,
I extend my gratitude to you with tea
instead of alcohol, Master Qi.
Master Qi,
since you're looking to
enter the ink industry,
why did you open a pawnshop
instead of an ink workshop?
Old Madam, I know my limits.
I only have
a superficial knowledge of ink.
Rushing into the ink industry could
easily be to my detriment.
It's better to...
It's better to test the ink makers
in Huizhou
and select the best by posing a challenge
about the ancient lacquer-soot ink.
Old Madam, that's an overstatement.
How would I dare to test
the prestigious ink makers here?
Given that Lord Yan has just taken office,
and that I'd like to do
some small business here,
I'm just riding the momentum
and seeking a lucky start.
As the saying goes, politics cannot
stay afloat without commerce.
In turn, proper governance builds
a stable commercial environment.
Master Qi,
you're running
quite a significant business here.
Old Madam,
whether my business is significant or not
depends on you.
Miss Li Zhen,
are you busy?
Old Madam asked me to bring you
some black tea.
Why don't you take a break
and enjoy a cup of tea?
No impurities. A fragrant smell.
Solid black and lustrous.
How nice.
This is really nice.
But its texture
is worlds apart from that
of the super-grade lampblack.
What a huge shame.
This is truly a shame.
Such a shame!
What do you want, Master Qi?
The Old Madam asked me
to bring you some black tea.
Would you like a cup of it?
Master Qi, you met with
the Seventh Old Madam
and then me.
Speak up.
What is it that you want?
Can't I just come check on the making
of the ancient lacquer-soot ink?
Don't close it.
You've opened it. Why rush to shut it?
I...
I do have a favor to ask.
Say it.
Miss Li Zhen, could you help me persuade
the Old Madam
to team up with me
on ink business?
If I remember correctly,
Master Qi,
you visited the Tian family
just the day before,
and then the Chen family.
Now, today, you insist on
cooperating with Li Ink.
What exactly is your purpose?
I am a businessman.
What purpose could I have?
Of course I am seeking
a business ally
who I can share weal and woes with.
The Li family aside,
Miss Li Zhen, if you are willing,
I can also cooperate with you.
Since you don't trust me, Master Qi,
and you're reluctant to tell the truth,
then there is nothing
we can talk about.
Please leave.
Miss Li Zhen, that's not right.
I am telling the truth.
Besides, think about it.
You've promised Lord Yan
to make the ancient lacquer-soot ink.
You can't back out from this game now.
So why not partner with me?
With my assistance,
you'll surely get twice the result
with half the effort.
I'm already in this game.
Master Qi, do you really not know
who got me
into this situation?
Please, Miss Li Zhen,
try not to assume the worst of others.
Perhaps the one who arranged this game
is playing
the black pieces like you are.
Wood's burning. Keep the draft away.
Got it.
I'll put the tea here.
Miss Li Zhen, it turns out
that you learned
such fine ink-making skills
from this ancient manual
on ink production.
This must be the Ink Chronicles
written by He Yuan.
You came back so soon.
Selling this book to me at 100 taels
wouldn't put you at a loss, you know?
Careful. This is the only existing copy.
This is the book, the Ink Chronicles.
Have someone ride a fast horse and deliver
this book to my brother.
The critical phase for ink making
has arrived now.
No mistakes are allowed.
Master Qi,
you're actually more knowledgeable
than I expected,
for having done studies
on ancient ink-making manuals.
Would you let go of this treasure,
Miss Li Zhen, painful as it may be?
I'll be glad to pay a handsome price
for the Ink Chronicles.
How very strange, Master Qi.
Why would you spend a fortune
on an old book?
It's the only copy
of this ancient classic
and of great collectible value.
It cannot be measured by gold or silver.
Then I'm afraid you'll be disappointed,
Master Qi.
May I ask, Miss Li Zhen,
how you got hold of this book?
I found it by chance. I got it as a gift.
I bought it from a shop.
Anyway, I didn't steal it
or rob anyone of it.
You must be joking, Miss Li Zhen.
I sincerely wish to buy this ancient book.
Is there anything wrong with me?
This book means a lot to me.
It taught me the basic truths of ink,
gave me the skills I need
to feed my family,
and set me on a long path of exploration.
This book serves
as a constant reminder for me,
that if I am to create my own Way of Ink,
then I must be concentrated
and stay away from distractions.
Therefore,
this book is a priceless treasure to me.
I will not sell it to anyone.
Understood.
I will not try to take away
what you cherish then.
I suppose, Miss Li Zhen,
this book cannot find
a better owner than you.
That said, may I borrow it
and read it here
for some time?
Suit yourself.
Just don't damage it.
Sure.
Miss Li Zhen,
are you seeking these "organs"?
So you've also done studies
on ink formulas,
Master Qi?
The human body contains 360 joints,
9 orifices, 5 solid organs
and 6 hollow organs.
I bet the organs mentioned here
refer to those inside animals.
That was also my guess before.
But that spot is smudged by ink.
So I can't tell the exact words.
Alright.
I offer to find these items for you,
Miss Li Zhen.
I will have them delivered
to your residence within 3 days.
This matter takes much effort.
I'd rather not trouble you with it,
Master Qi.
I'll handle it myself.
Please give me some time, Miss Li Zhen.
I promise I will show you my sincerity
in cooperating with the Li family.
Fine, whatever.
Why mumble so much while reading the book?
Give it back to me.
I want it back.
I haven't finished burning the wood.
You're being a hindrance here.
Save whatever you have to say for later.
Please leave.
Off you go.
Leave the room.
Hurry. Just go.
Better keep the draft away.
Is Zhen
making any progress
in the ink workshop?
It's very difficult
to recreate lacquer-soot ink.
Not to mention Zhen—
even the Sixth Master
hasn't made much progress.
To add to that...
Anything wrong?
Workers from senior levels
like Manager Shao
to the bottom levels
in the ink workshop are all against her.
I guess these few days
must be hard for Zhen.
Mother,
given that, I'm wondering
if I should
go give Master Sun
a heads-up.
If Zhen is really
looking to launch a career
in the ink-making industry,
whether she returns to the family
or starts everything on her own,
she'll have to earn everyone's support
in the ink workshop.
This is a challenge she has to overcome.
Years ago, your father,
the Sixth Master, and the Eighth Uncle
all went through the same rough patch.
This is not right.
How is it not right?
The raw materials are not
in the right amount or proportions.
How am I supposed to mix them up
and make lampblack?
This won't do.
I must ask Manager Shao about it.
Manager Shao,
the raw materials
that Doggie brought to my smoke shed
were handled by you, right?
Yes, exactly.
Is there a problem?
Those raw materials
are in different amount
and proportions
from what's written on this list.
How am I supposed to mix them up
to make lampblack?
Miss Li Zhen,
you've taken things from other smoke sheds
multiple times.
I know you're working hard to make ink,
so I've never held you accountable.
Given that, this time
when I distributed materials,
I deducted the corresponding amount.
So you did deduct some of them.
But without enough raw materials,
how do I make lampblack?
Has it ever occurred to you, Miss Li Zhen,
that how others could make lampblack
with you taking their materials away?
They might get anxious
and ask for next month's materials.
What would that lead to?
I...
Miss Li Zhen,
you've been learning ink making
from Eighth Master Li.
Do you know
who designed this registration book
that you hate most?
Who?
Couldn't be my grandpa, could it?
Decades ago,
the old master of the Li family passed
way too early.
The Sixth, Seventh, and Eighth Masters
were too young
to control the workshop employees.
Thus, Li Ink gradually declined.
Later,
the Seventh Master held the fort,
while the Eighth Master
worked day and night to develop new ink,
and the Sixth Master traveled everywhere
to collect materials and deliver goods.
The Seventh Old Madam
managed issues at home.
That way, Li Ink was finally stabilized,
and reached the prime
where it competed several times
for the privilege to produce tribute ink.
By then, I had just joined Li Ink
as an apprentice
who ran errands a lot like Doggie.
The Eighth Master took me with him
and set up rules for Li Ink,
registering every detail
in this book, however trivial that was.
Miss Li Zhen,
obeying rules is the basis
of accompliments.
People respectfully
refer to the Eighth Master
as head of the Five Ink-making
Grandmasters of the dynasty.
Do you think it's just
because of his exquisite skills?
I don't have much talent in making ink.
After spending my entire life
learning from him,
the only thing I've picked up
is "caution."
And that already makes me feel
I've benefited a lot.
There is so much more you need to learn
from your grandfather.
Back then, was my grandfather
as indifferent
as you are now?
The Eighth Master kept this log himself.
Take a look.
[Manifest of Materials
for the Ink Workshop]
It was made in the year I was born.
I didn't know Grandpa would often record
what the Sixth Grandfather did.
[Li Jingfu]
My father's doing
was actually recorded as well.
Manager Shao,
I was wrong before.
I accept the punishment.
I dare not have you bow.
I am merely strictly following
the rules of Li Ink.
To be honest, Miss Li Zhen,
when you first arrived,
I did have some doubts.
But after a few days' observation,
I can tell that you've been humble
and working hard day and night
with one single focus
on recreating
the ancient lacquer-soot ink.
I've really found you admirable.
Manager Shao, please don't.
I should be the one
paying respects to you.
This has never happened before.
We demand an explanation!
What's going on?
Manager Shao.
You're also here, Miss Li Zhen.
That's even better.
Manager Shao,
this is the lampblack
made by Master Wei yesterday.
Look.
Such a mess, isn't it?
It's all thanks to Miss Li Zhen.
She sneaked into the ink workshop
at midnight and let the wind in.
The lampblack
is completely ruined.
Manager Shao,
I did do wrong by rashly entering
the ink workshop last night,
which violated the rules
for using smoke sheds.
But when I arrived
at that very smoke shed yesterday,
there was no one
or finished lampblack at all.
Young lady,
stop talking nonsense and shifting blame.
I spent all of yesterday
making lampblack in that smoke shed.
Indeed, I saw it with my own eyes.
Did you also see it as well?
-Yes!
-That's right!
Manager Shao,
if my memory serves me right,
every action in the ink workshop,
including using smoke sheds,
and collecting lamp oil,
raw materials, and other supplies,
must be registered by you.
Am I right?
That's the standard procedure.
Yesterday, I personally asked Shao
for permission
to use that smoke shed.
Check out the log if you don't believe me.
You did use that smoke shed yesterday.
But there isn't a record
of you collecting raw materials
for making lampblack.
Then where did you source
the materials for making that lampblack?
I... I...
Could it be that you, Mr. Wei,
violated the rules first by taking
materials without registering?
Manager Shao,
I remember you once told me
that in the ink workshop,
taking materials without registering
is equal to stealing.
No, no.
P-Perhaps I just used
t-the leftover materials
from a few days ago.
I-I can't remember clearly.
It was 7 days ago
when you last collected raw materials.
But you already delivered products
the day before yesterday.
I also checked the smoke sheds.
There were no leftovers.
I have such a bad memory.
This lampblack was a failed product
from a few days ago.
Due to my packed schedule,
I forgot to have it registered.
It has nothing to do with Miss Li Zhen.
Since it's a misunderstanding,
Mr. Wei,
please apologize to Miss Li Zhen.
The ink workshop is busy and crowded.
So I got confused.
My apologies, Miss Li Zhen.
No worries.
Everyone, leave.
Go to work.
Thanks, Manager Shao.
Grandpa,
was Dad punished with a fine
back when he worked in the ink workshop?
More than just a fine.
There are strict rules
in the ink workshop.
Your grandpa always said
it was no easy job for the workers
to support their families.
So he couldn't bear
to impose a large fine.
Therefore, at the end,
all the responsibility
was piled onto your dad.
You weren't even born back then.
Zhengliang might remember it.
There was a time when your grandpa
withheld a whole month's salary
from your dad as punishment.
Your dad hadn't a dime
or the guts to tell me the truth.
Guess what he did?
Your dad actually secretly went through
my dowry in the middle of the night.
I caught him red-handed!
One night, you chased Dad around,
beat him,
and even got out of the house.
That was the night, right?
Mother, is it true?
Of course it's true.
He had the gall to steal my dowry.
I was furious!
Therefore,
Zhen, Qiu'e,
keep this in mind:
make sure you hide your dowries well
in the future.
Men,
all the men,
are like turnips.
Father, I'm not talking about you.
Mother.
Thank you, Mother.
Is my brother a turnip too?
Your brother?
He's as dumb as a turnip!
Mother.
She's saying you're as dumb as a turnip!
Come on, eat more turnips.
I want some too.
Dig in!
Zhengliang, have more turnips.
Keep quiet please.
Zhen.
Follow Shao An's lead
and learn from him.
I might not be able
to teach you what he can.
I know.
How is the lampblack coming along?
Once animal fat is added,
there will be oil slicks
that can't be washed away.
I've tried several methods,
but the results are not very ideal.
That said, don't worry, Grandpa.
I already have a clue about this matter.
If worst comes to worst,
I'll try out the six bowels of those livestock one by one.
I'll eventually find
a suitable combination.
That's good.
Hurry and eat up.
I don't know what kind of livestock
or what kind of internal organ it uses.
Trying out the combinations
will take nearly 100 attempts.
When will this end?
Miss Li Zhen, it seems
that you still don't believe me.
I never pin my hopes on other people.
The purest internal organ
is the gallbladder.
Over the past few days,
I have been rushing about day and night,
visiting numerous great scholars.
Only then did I confirm that what was
recorded in the ancient text
is the purest internal organ.
I apologize for my attitude before.
Please don't take offense, Master Qi.
Not at all.
However, although I have confirmed
that the ancient text
refers to the purest internal organ,
as for exactly which animal's bile it is,
I...
Master Qi, you have already
helped me a lot.
I can handle the rest myself.
Please.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
Is there anything else, Master Qi?
If there is nothing else,
please see yourself out.
Please.
Alright.
It's done?
Eighth Master Li.
Eighth Master Li!
Eighth Master Li...
Zhen recreated the long-lost
supreme-grade ancient
lacquer lampblack.
Father.
It's almost done.
Jingdong.
Stop working on it.
Zhen has succeeded.
She successfully recreated
the supreme-grade lampblack
of the ancient lacquer-soot ink.
Seventh Grandmother,
I
made it.
Zhen.
Now that this lacquer lampblack is
a great success,
Li Ink
can be saved.
Zhen.
It was you
who saved Li Ink.
I'd like to thank you
on behalf of Li Ink.
Seventh Grandmother.
Mother.
Please get up.
I can't accept this.
You don't need to thank me.
It's what I should do.
The lampblack's ingredient combination
for the ancient lacquer-soot ink
has been worked out.
To completely restore
the ancient lacquer-soot ink,
there are still countless processes.
Today, I
completely entrust
this important matter
to you.
Please rest assured.
I
will not let you down.
Hundreds of thousands of hammerings
with a weak gelatin binder.
One strike less
would disgrace the Li family’s name.
Mother, we must have faith in Zhen.
[Li Ink]
Zhen is here!
Put on clothes!
I-I'm fine.
You can continue.
No need to get dressed.
I'm not looking!
I'm not looking! I'm not looking!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Miss Li Zhen.
Manager Shao.
Look at her.
Old Madam.
Aunt Rujun.
This is the ancient lacquer-soot ink
recreated by Zhen.
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter?
Why did you use the four seasons
as the carving pattern?
This was Zhen's proposal.
She said the Four Seasons painting
reflects the difficulty of ink-making
and her wish that fine ink
may stay with people for a long time—
its ink never fading through
the four seasons of the year.
Right.
The gold tracing on it
was personally drawn by Manager Shao.
I'm ashamed.
I've followed Eighth Master Li
for half my life.
I didn't master ink-making,
only picked up the basics.
Seventh Grandmother.
How well
have I restored this ink?
Excellent.
Zhen.
A single ink stick requires hundreds
of soot firing,
over ten thousand hammerings
to bind the glue,
and still must be carved,
molded, and air-dried.
Making ink is no easy task.
Here,
lies the hard work
of all the ink-maker in the ink workshop.
I understand.
Grandpa!
Grandpa.
I recreated
the lacquer-soot ink.
When making the lacquer-soot ink,
if your mind drifts,
the ink loses its depth
and becomes shallow.
This ink
[Beauty in All Four Seasons]
is firm as jade.
Li Ink prizes a spirit
of unyielding integrity.
True backbone.